Many strange legends are told of these jungles of India,
有人印度从林 流传着许许多多的传说
but none so strange as the story of a small boy named Mowgli.
其中最离奇的要数一个 叫毛克力男孩的故事
It all began when the silence of the jungle was broken
一切都是从罕静的从林
by an unfamiliar sound.
被不陌生的声音打破 开始的
It was a sound like one never heard before
那是一个在这片从林中 从未听到过的
in this part of the jungle.
声音
lt was amancub!
是个人孩儿 !
Had I known how deeply ! was to be involved,
如果知道后来 我会深陷其中
! would've obeyed my first impulse and walked away.
我会依照最初的念头走开
This man cub would have to have nourishment, and soon.
这个人孩儿需要有人来喂养
lt was many days’ travel to the nearest man-village,
可到最近的人类层住的村庄 也需要几天的路程
and without a mother's care, he would soon perish.
没有母亲的呵折 他很快就会死去
Then it occurred to me.
这时我突然想起了
A family of wolves I knew
我所认识的一对狼夫妇
had been blessed with a litter of cubs.
他们刚好哺养着一群孩子
! knew there'd be no problem with the mother,
我觉得母亲不会有问题
thanks to the maternal instinct,
因为这是母性的本能
but l wasn't so sure about Rama, the father.
但我不敢肯定他们的父亲 拉玛的态度如何
Ten times, the rains had come and gone,
雨季来了10玫 又走了10次
and I often stopped by to see how Mowgli, the man cub, was getting along.
我经常要到这里停一停 看看毛克力 人和孩儿的情况
He was a favorite with all the young wolf cubs of the pack.
他是这群小狼中所穹爱的
No man cub was ever happier.
没有比他更幸福的孩子了
And yet, I knew that someday
不过 我知道早晚有一天
he would have to go back to his own kind.
他会回到属于他的 那个世界中去
Then one night, the wolf pack elders met at Council Rock
一天晚上 狼群长老们 聚集在议会石前开会
because Shere Khan, the tiger,
因为老虎施亚汗
had returned to their part of the jungle.
又回到了这片从林中
This meeting was to change the man cub's entire future.
他们开会商量要改变 人孩儿的命运
Shere Khan will surely kill the boy and all who try to protect him.
施亚汗一定会杀死男孩 和那些想保扩他的人
Now, are we all in agreement as to what must be done?
现在我们是否都同意 将要采取的措施 ?
Now it is my unpleasant duty to tell the boy's father.
我很不情愿地要 告诉那个男孩儿的父亲
Rama. Come over here, please.
拉玛 请你过来一下
Yes, Akela?
是 阿吉拉?
The council has reached its decision.
议会已经做出了决定
The man cub can no longer stay with the pack.
人和孩儿不能 再采在狼群中了
He must leave at once.
他必须立刻离开
"Leave"?
[离开」 ?
I'm sorry, Rama. There is no other way.
抱火 拉玛 没有别的办法
But the man cub is...
可是这个人孩几…
Well, he's like my own son.
就像我自己的孩子一样
Surely he's entitled to the protection of the pack.
他应该享有狼群的保扩
But, Rama, even the strength of the pack
可是 拉玛 即使有狼群的保扩
is no match for the tiger.
也不足以对付老虎
But the boy cannot survive alone in the jungle.
可和孩子不可能单独 在从林里生活
Akela, perhaps I can be of help.
阿吉拉 或许 我可以帮忙
You, Bagheera? How?
你 巴赫拉?了怎么帮?
I know of a man-village where he'll be safe.
我知道一然人类居住的村庄 他在那里会安全的
Mowgli and I have taken many walks into the jungle together.
我和毛克力以前经常 在从林里散步
I'm sure he'll go with me.
我相信他愿意和我一起走
So be it. Now there's no time to lose.
那就这么定了 抓紧时间吧
Good luck.
祝你走运
Bagheera, I'm getting a little sleepy.
巴赫拉 我有点儿困了
Shouldn't we start back home?
我们是不是该回家了?
Mowgli, this time we're not going back.
毛克力 这炊我们 不往回走了
- I'm taking you to a man-village. - But why?
我要带你去人类居住的村庄 可这是为什么?
Because Shere Khan has returned to this part of the jungle...
因为施亚汗 又回到了这片从林中…
..and he has sworn to kill you.
…他发誓要杀了你
Kill me? But why would he want to do that?
杀了我 ? 他为什么要这样做 ?
He hates man.
他恨人类
Shere Khan is not going to allow you to grow up to become a man,
施亚汗是不会让你长大成人
just another hunter with a gun.
成为另一个拿枪的猎人的
We'll just explain to him that I'd never do a thing like that.
我们可以向他解释 我决不会做那样的事
Nonsense. No one explains anything to Shere Khan.
一派胡言 施亚汗 从不听任何人的解释
Well, maybe so, but I'm not afraid.
也许是这样 可我不怕
- And besides, I... - Now, that's enough.
此外  我…- 行了 不要再说了
We'll spend the night here.
我们就在这里过夜
Things will look better in the morning.
明天早上一切都会好起来的
Man Cub?
人孩儿 ?
Man Cub!
人孩儿 !
Now, come on. Up this tree. It's safer up there.
快来 铃到树上去 上边儿会安全些
I don't wanna go back to the man-village.
我不想回人类层住的村庄
Go on. Up you go.
上吧 息上去
- That limb way up there? - That's right.
扑到那个枝权上去吗 ? 没错几
Is that all the better you can climb?
这就是你爬树的本事 ?
It's too big around.
这树太粗了
And besides, I don't have any claws.
况且 我没不子
Now get some sleep.
好了 了瞧觉吧
We've got a long journey ahead of us tomorrow.
明天我们还有很长的路要走呢
l wanna stay in the jungle.
我想采在丛林里
Huh? You wouldn't last one day.
这是你在从林里的最后一晚了
I'm not afraid.
我不害怕
I can look out for myself.
我自己会小心的
$-S-S-Say, now.
说说吧 现在
What have we here?
瞧这是谁呀?
It's a man cub.
是个人孩几
A delic-i-ous man cub.
可口味美的人孩儿
Oh, go away and leave me alone.
哦 走开点儿 别理我
Oh, that's just what I should do, but I'm not.
哦 我原本是该走开 可我现在不能
Oh, now, please go to sleep, Man Cub.
好了 拜托你快睡吧 人孩儿
Yes-s-s-s, Man Cub.
是的 人孩儿
Pleas-s-se go to sleep
拜托你快盯吧
S-S-Sleep, little man cub
取吧 小人和孩儿
Rest in peace
安息吧
Sleep.
取吧
Bagheera...
巴赫拉…
Oh, now... now, look, there's no use arguing anymore.
哦 听着 再争吵也没用
Now, no more talk till morning.
哦 有话明天再说吧
He won't be here in the morning.
明天他就不在这儿了
Huh? Oh, yes, he will. I...
嗯?哦 是的 他会 我…
Kaa! Hold it, Kaa!
卡奥!慢着 卡奥!
My sinus-s-s-s-s.
我的身子
You have just made a s-s-s-serious mistake, my friend,
你犯了一个严重的错误 我的朋友
a very s-s-s-stupid...
非常愚蠢的…
Now, Kaa, I was...
听着 卡奥 我是…
..mistake.
…错误
Look me in the eye when I'm speaking to you.
我说话的时候看着我的眼睛
No, please, Kaa...
不 拜托了 卡奥…
Both eyes, if you please.
两只眼睛 如果你不介意的话
You have just
你已经结束了
s-S-s-sealed your doom.
自己的小命儿
Look, Bagheera.
看 巴赫拉
Look. Bagheera. Wake up, Bagheera.
看呀 巴赫拉 醒醒 巴赫拉
Wha...?
怎么回事?
Just you wait till l get you in my coils.
你等着 下灵我非把你缠死
Bagheera, he's got a knot in his tail!
巴赫拉 他的尾巴打结了
"He's got a knot in his tail."
「 他的尾巴打结了1
This is going to slow down
这样会减慢
my s-s-s-slithering.
我的想行速度
So, you can look out for yourself, can you?
这么说 你可以 照顾自己了 是吗?
So, you want to stay in the jungle, do you?
这么说你想采在从林里 是吗?
Yes, I wanna stay in the jungle.
是的 我想呆在从林里
Now, now, for the last time, go to sleep.
现在我最后再说一遍 快陵吧
Man cub.
人孩儿
Hup, two, three, four
二三四
Keep it up Two, three, four
跟上队伍 二 三 四
A parade!
巡逻队 !
Oh, no.
哦 不
The dawn patrol again.
又在清晨巡还
Company... sound off!
全体都有…唱!
Oh, the aim of our patrol
哦 我们巡逻的目的
ls a question rather droll
是相当滑稽的问题
For to march and drill over field and hill
跨田野 过上没 为了行军和训练
Is a military goal
这是一个军事目的
Hup, two, three, four
二三四
Dress it up, two, three, four
排好队 二 三 四
By the ranks or single file
排成横列或单列纵队
Over every jungle mile
跨过每片丛林
Oh, we stamp and crush through the underbrush
哦 我们践踏踩压 穿过树丛
In the military style
以军队的方式
Hello. What are you doing?
喂 你们在干什么 ?
Drilling.
在训练
- Can I do it too? - Sure. Just do what I do.
我也能训练吗 ? 当然 我怎么做你就怎么做
But don't talk in ranks. It's against regulations.
但在队列中不许说话 这是违反条例的
To the rear... march!
向后转…走!
The other way. Turn around.
向反方向 转过身去
Hup, two, three, four
二三四
Keep it up, two, three, four
跟上队伍 二 三 四
To the rear...
向后转…
.-ho!
…走1
Company... halt!
全体都有…立定 !
That means "stop."
那意思是「停下1
Company... left face!
全体都有…向左转 !
March, march, march.
行军 行军 行军
My feet are killing me.
我的脚疼死了
I'm puttin’ in for a transfer to another herd.
我要打报告申请调往 另外的象群
Silence in the ranks!
队列里不许说话 !
Dress up that line.
看齐
Pull it in, Winifred.
收回去些 威妮弗蔷德
Inspection...
检查…
.-arms!
…武器 !
Stick your nose out.
把鼻子伸出去
- Like this? - That's right.
像这样 ? 对
A dusty muzzle.
鼻孔里都是友本
Soldier, remember: in battle, that trunk can save your life.
士兵 记住 : 战场上 鼻子可以择救你的生命
Take good care of it, my man.
好好爱扩吧 士兵
- Yes, sir. - Very good. Carry on.
是 长官 很好 继续
Let's have a little more spit and polish on those bayonets.
吐点唾沫把刺刀探亮些
Yes, sir.
是 长官
Esprit de corps.
要有集体精神
That's the way I earned my commission
正是由于有这种精神 我才在马哈拉查
in the Maharajah's Fifth Pachyderm Brigade.
第五厚皮类动物旅中 晋升到了今天的位置
Back in '88, it was... Or was it?
想当年 我是那么… 对不对?
Here it comes. The Victoria Cross bit again.
又来了 又讲他的维多利亚十字勋章
It was then I received the Victoria Cross,
就是在那年 我获得了维多利亚十字助章
for bravery above and beyond the call of duty.
因为我有大无司的勇敢精神
Those were the days.
就是那些日子
Discipline! Discipline was the thing.
纪律 ! 纪律是最重要的
Builds character and that sort of thing, you know.
能塑造人的特质 懂吗
Where was I?
我说到哪儿了?
Oh, yes. Inspection.
哦 是的 检查
Well, very good.
好 很好
Wipe off that silly grin, soldier. This is the army.
别寻皮笑脸的 士兵 这里是部队
Eyes front.
向前看
Lieutenant, that haircut is not regulation.
中尉 你的头发不符合标准
Rather on the gaudy side, don't you think?
华而不实 你不觉得吗 ?
There. That's better.
草态 这样还差不多
And as for you...
至于你…
Oh, there you are.
哦 你在这儿史
Let's keep those heels together, shall we, son?
我们把脚后跟儿并齐 好不好 儿子?
OK, Pop.
是 区和区
- Sir. - Yes, now that's better.
长宫 是的 这样就好多了
Well, a new recruit, eh?
哦 是新兵吗?
- l say, what happened to your trunk? - Hey!
我说 你的鼻子是怎么搞的? 哩1 os
Stop that!
别暑析 !
A man cub! Ohh, this is treason! Sabotage!
是人孩儿 !哦 这是叛变 ! 是阴谋破坏 !
I'll have no man cub in my jungle!
我不能让人孩儿采在 我的从林里!
- It's not your jungle! - Hold it! Hold it!
这不是你的从林 ! 慢着 ! 慢着 !
Il can explain, Hathi.
我来解释 哈菇
Colonel Hathi, if you please, sir.
最好加上上校 先生
Oh, yes, yes. Colonel Hathi.
哦 是的 哈莆上校
The man cub is with me. I'm taking him back to the man-village.
人孩儿是和我一起来的 我要带他去人类居住的村庄
- To stay? - You have the word of Bagheera.
住下去吗 ? 这是巴赫拉的保证
Good.
很好
And remember, an elephant never forgets.
记住 大象永远不会忘记
I don't know what the army's coming to these days.
我不知道现在要军队干什么
These young whippersnappers. Who do they think they are?
这些自以为了不起的年轻人 他们以为自己是谁?
Let's get on with it!
我们继续操练 !
Right face!
向右转 !
Dear, haven't you forgotten something?
亲爱的 你是不是忘了什么 ?
Nonsense, Winifred, old girl.
胡说 威妮弗蔓德
An elephant never forgets.
大象什么也不会忘记
Well, you just forgot our son.
你把我们的儿子给忘了
Our... Son? Son!
我们的…儿子?儿子!
Oh, yes, yes, yes. Quite right.
哦 是的 是的 没错儿
To the rear... march!
向后转…走!
When I grow up, I'm gonna be a colonel just like my...
等我长大以后 也要当上校 就像我的…
If I've told you once, I've told you a thousand times...
我对你说过无数炊了…
Pop! Look out!
和爸和爸 1小心!
Gee, Pop, you forgot to say “halt.”
和葡和爸 你总了说「立定」 了
He said an elephant never forgets.
他还说大象什么也不会忘呢
It's not funny.
这并不好笑
Let's get out of here quick before anything else happens.
在发生什么意外之前 我们赶快离开这里
Bagheera! Where are we goin'?
巴赫拉!我们到哪儿去 ?
You're going back to the man-village right now.
你现在要去人类居住的村庄
I'm not going.
我不去
- Oh, yes, you are. - I'm staying right here.
哦 是的 你要去 我就采在这儿了
You're going, if l have to drag you every step of the way.
你要去 不然我就把你拖去
Let go, you...
我们走 你…
You let go of me!
你松开我 !
Oh, that does it.
哦 那好吧
I've had it, Man Cub.
我受够了 人和孩儿
From now on, you're on your own...
从现在起 你自己管自己吧…
.-alone!
…一个人 !
Don't worry about me.
别为我担心
Foolish man cub.
愚夸的人孩儿
Doo-bee, doo-bee Doo-bee-dee-doo
咯吡 咯吡 咯吡 咬叶
Well, it's a-doo-bah-dee-doo
我是嘟吐咬叶
Yes, it's a-doo-bah-dee-doo
是的 我是叶叶中嘟
! mean, a-doo-bee, doo-bee Doo-bee, doo-bee
我是说 一个叶吡叶吡 嘟吡吡
Doo-bee-dee-doo
嘟吡咬
And with...
还有…-
Well, now.
哩
What have we here?
瞧这是谁呀?
Hey!
哩1 区
What a funny little bit of a...
多有趣的一个小…
- Ooh! - Go away!
哦 ! 走开 !
Oh, boy, I've seen everything in these woods.
哦 孩子 在这林子里 我什么事都见过
Ooh, what have I run on?
哦 我这是撞到谁了?
- What a pretty thing this is. - Leave me alone.
这是多好的一件事几 别烦我
Well, now, that's pretty big talk, little britches.
嘿 这口气可够大的 傲慢的人
I'm big enough.
我已经长大了
Pitiful.
可怜
Hey, kid, you need help
嘿 孩子 你需要帮助
and ol' Baloo's gonna learn you to fight like a bear.
老巴鲁来教教你 如何像狗驴一样打如
Come on. I'm gonna show ya.
来吧 我让你看看
Yeah!
是的!
All right, now, kid, loosen up.
好的 孩子 放松
Get real loose, then start to weave. Weave a little. Now, move.
一定要放松 然后开始晃动 现在移动脚步
That's it. Now give me a big bear growl.
对 现在像狗熊一样 鸣哮一声
Scare me.
吓距我
Oh, boy.
莪 孩子
I'm talkin’ about like a big bear.
我像一只大狗熊一样在说话
He's in trouble.
他遇到麻烦了
I shouldn't have left him alone.
我不该把他一个人抛下
- Abig one, right from your toes. - How's that?
大声点儿 从脚下头用力 这回呢?
You're gettin’ it, kid.
差不多了 孩子
Oh, no! It's Baloo!
哦 不!是巴鲁!
That shiftless, stupid jungle bum.
那个无能蚌夺的丛林无赖
Weave about now. Look for an opening.
来回晃动 寻找机会
Keep movin’. Keep...
动起来 动…
You're gettin’ it, kid. Come on! That's it!
你快学会了 孩子 再来 ! 很好 !
He's a dandy!
他是个花花公子 !
Fine teacher you are, Ol' Iron Paws.
你可真是个好老病 老铁不
Thanks, Bagheera.
谢谢 巴赫拉
Tell me, tell me, after you knock your pupil senseless,
告诉我 你把学生打得失去知觉
how do you expect him to remember the lesson, hmm?
如何能证他记住这个教训?
Well, I...
哦 我…
Well, I didn't mean to lay it on him so hard.
我并没想使劲儿打他
I'm not hurt. I'm all right.
我没受伤 我好着呢
I'm a lot tougher than some people think.
我比一些人认为的 要结实得多
You better believe it.
你最好还是相信
Now, let's go once more.
来 我们再来一次
l want you to keep circlin’, or I'm gonna knock your roof in again.
我要你一直转园 不然我又要把你打倒了
You'd better keep movin’...
你最好不停地移动…
Hey! Right on the button.
嘿 正中下巴
No. No, now, we don't do that here in the jun... No!
不 不 我们不玩儿这个了 不 !
No, you're ticklin’. I can't stand that ticklin’.
不 你在挠我的痒痒 我受不了啦
Help! Bagheera!
救命 ! 巴赫拉 1!
Oh, boy. That's all he needs, more confidence.
哦 伙计 他需要这个 更多的自信
- Give up, Baloo? - I give up, I told ya!
投不投降 巴恒? 我投降 我投降 !
Hey!
哩1 区
You know somethin'? You're all right, kid.
知道吗 ? 你真的不错 孩子
What do they call you?
别人叫你什么 ?
Mowgli, and he's going back to the man-village right now.
毛克力 他现在要回 人居住的村庄去
Man-village? They'll ruin ‘im! They'll make a man out of him.
人居住的村庄 ? 他会被毁了 ! 他们会把他塑造成一个人
Oh, Baloo, I wanna stay here with you.
巴鲁 我想和你采在这里
Certainly, you do.
你当然可以
Oh? And just how do you think he will survive?
哦?那你觉得 他怎样才能活下去?
"How do you think..." What do you mean, how do you think he...
「那你觉得…1 你说这话是什么意思…
He's with me, ain't he? And I'll learn him all l know.
不是有我在吗 对吗 ? 我会把所有本领都教给他
Oh? That shouldn't take too long.
哦?这不会用很和久
Look, now, it's like this, little britches.
听着 例慢的人 得像这样
All you gotta do is...
你所要做的就是…
Look for the bare necessities
寻找必需品
The simple bare necessities
简简单单的必需品
Forget about your worries and your strife
忘记你的烦恼和争吵
1 mean, the bare necessities
我是说 必需品
Are Mother Nature's recipes
是大地之母的误饪方法
That bring the bare necessities of life
给予了我们生活的必需品
Wherever I wander
不论我走向何方
Wherever I roam
不管我漫步何然
! couldn't be fonder
我决不会是
Of my big home
自己家中的策蛋
The bees are buzzin' in the tree
蜜蜂在树从中喻喻作唤
When you look under the rocks and plants
翻起石头和树干 在下面寻找
And take a glance at the fancy ants
看一限那可爱的妈蚊
Then maybe try a few
也许可以尝一口
You eat ants?
你吃蚂蚁 ?
Ha ha! You better believe it.
哈哈 ! 你就放心吧
And you're gonna love the way they tickle.
你会喜欢那种痒痒的感觉的
Mowgli, look out!
毛克力 小心 !
The bare necessities of life will come to you
将会呈现在你眼前
But when?
什么时候?
They'll come to you
他们会到你的跟前来
Look for the bare necessities
寻找必需品
The simple bare necessities
简简单单的必需品
Forget about your worries and your strife
忘掉你的烦恼和争吵
1 mean, the bare necessities
我是说 必须品
That's why a bear can rest at ease
这就是为什么 狗熊可以遂东自在
With just the bare necessities of life
只索取生活必需品
Now, when you pick a pawpaw
当你摘取木瓜
Or a prickly pear
或者仙人果的时候
And you prick a raw paw Well, next time beware
你刺疼了手掌 下一均一定要记住
Don't pick the prickly pear by the paw
不要用手去搞亿人果
When you pick a pear try to use the claw
当你去搞梨子的时候 要用你的直子
But you don't need to use the claw
但是当你去搞木瓜的时候
When you pick a pear of the big pawpaw
就没必要去使用爪子
Have I given you a clue?
你明白这秘诀了吗 ?
Golly, thanks, Baloo.
天哪 谢谢 巴章
"Pawpaw." Of all the silly gibberish.
「 木瓜」 一派胡言
Come on, Baggy, get with the beat.
来吧 巴赫拉 一起跳
The bare necessities of life will come to you
生活必需品 将会呈现在你眼前
- They'll come to me! - They'll come to you
会呈现在我的眼前 ! 会呈现在你的眼前 !
How ‘bout scratchin' that left shoulder while you're up there, Mowgli?
帮我挠捞的堪悦 毛克力 既然你想到了我的背上
No. Just a hair lower.
不 稍微往下点几
There. Right there. That's it.
对 就那儿 就那几
This is beautiful. That's good.
太和舒服了 太好了
Kid, we've got to get to a tree. This calls for some big scratchin’.
孩子 我们得找一棵树 这叫大畔痒税
You're lots of fun, Baloo.
你太有趣了 巴恒
Right on it.
靠在上面
Yeah!
是的!
That's delicious.
太美了
Just a little bit...
只是有点儿…-
Yeah!
是的!
Oh, man. This is really livin’.
哦 伙计 这才是真正的生活
So just try and relax. Yeah.
想办法放松 对
Cool it.
凉快凉快
Fall apart in my backyard.
在我的后院里放松放松
‘Cause let me tell you somethin’, little britches...
让我来给你讲讲吧 傲慢的人…
If you act like that bee...
你如果像那只蜜峰一样…
You're workin’ too hard.
那你就太累了
And don't spend your time...
不要花费你的时间…
.-lookin' around...
…四然寻找…
..for something you want...
…寻找你想要的…
. that can't be found.
…那些根本找不到的东西
When you find out you can live without it
当你发现没有它 你照样能生活
And go along not thinkin’ about it
那你就不要去想它
lil tell you somethin’ true
我告诉你真话
The bare necessities of life will come to you
将呈现在你面前
I give up.
我放弃了
Well, l hope his luck holds out.
我希望他的运气能持久
Mowgli, how about you singin'?
毛克力 你来唱唱如何?
Look for the bare necessities
寻找必需品
The simple bare necessities
简简单单的必需品
Forget about your worries and your strife
忘掉你的烦恼和争吵
- Yeah, man! - ! mean, the bare necessities
是的 人饮计 ! 我是说 必须品
That's why a bear can rest at ease
这就是为什么 狗熊能够遂唤自在
With just the bare necessities of life
只索取生活必需品
Yeah!
是的!
Yeah, man
是的 伙计
Beautiful. That's real jungle harmony.
太美了 这才是真正的和谐从林
That's my boy.
真是我的好孩子
You're gonna make one swell bear.
你会成为一只出色的狗熊
Why, you even sing like one.
怎么 你唱歌的样子就像狗能
Yeah.
是的
Doo-bee-doo
嘻 吡咯
Aye-bee doogie-woogie doo
啊吡响咏鸣纪痢
Hey, Mowgli, how about you flickin' that ol’ mean fly
嘿 毛克力 你能不能 把那只讨厌的苍蝇
off of your papa bear's nose?
从和多和葡的鼻子上赶走?
Boy, when you flick a fly, you really...
孩子 让你打签晶 你怎么…
Why, you flat-nosed, little-eyed, flaky creep!
你为什么要打我的鼻子 小眼睛的讨厌家伙 !
Hey! Let go of me!
嘿!放开我 !
Take your flea-pickin’ hands off of my cub!
把你们那些捉改子的手 从我孩子身上拿开 !
Come on and get 'im, champ!
来呀 抓住他 冠军 !
- He ain't no champ! He's a chump! - Baloo!
他不是冠军 ! 他是冠军 ! 巴鲁 !
Yeah! A big hothead!
是的 ! 一个傻大儿 !
OK, you guys asked for it. I'll...
好 你们可是自找的 我要…
That'll cool 'im off!
这会让他冷静些 !
Gimme back my man cub!
把我的人孩儿还我 !
Here he is! Come and get ‘im!
他在这儿 ! 过来拿吧 !
That's how a bear can rest at ease!
狗熊就是这样遂遗自在的!
Here's some bare necessities!
这儿有些必需品 !
Now, just try that again, you...
你们再来试试 你们…
- What's that you hit him with, son? - That was a bare necessity!
儿予 你用什么东西打他 ? 是必需品 !
You turn him loose, or I'll jerk a knot in your tail!
你放开他 不然我把你的尾巴打成结!
We give up!
我们不玩儿了 !
Here he comes!
他飞过去了 !
Baloo! Catch me!
巴鲁 ! 接住我 !
- Baloo! - Back up! Back up! Faster! Faster!
巴鲁 ! 往后退 !往后退!快!快!
Faster!
快点 !
Arolling bear gathers no hair!
滚动的狗熊不长毛 !
Baloo, help me!
巴鲁 救救我 !
Baloo! They're carrying me away!
巴鲁 ! 他们把我带走了 !
Bagheera!
巴赫拉!
Well, it's happened.
果然出事了
Took a little longer than I thought, but it's happened.
比我想的时间长了点几 但还是出事了
Bagheera!
巴赫拉!
Oh, you heard me, huh?
哦 你听到了 是吗?
Mowgli. Mowgli!
毛克力 毛克力!
All right, what happened? Where's Mowgli?
好了 出什么事儿了? 毛克力在哪儿?
They ambushed me.
我中了他们的埋伏
Thousands of 'em.
他们有上千人
I jabbed with my left, then I swung with a right...
我用堪手打 然后又用右手劈…
Oh, for the last time, what happened to Mowgli?
哦 我最后再说一遍 毛克力到底怎么了?
Like I told ya, them mangy monkeys carried him off!
我没告诉你吗 很多猴子把他抢跑了
The ancient ruins.
十废沪
Ohh, I hate to think what will happen when he meets that king of theirs.
真不敢想 他见到那个国王时 会发生什么事
Dah dee-ding dah-ding-ding
达一吐一叮一达一叮一叮
Oh, lode diddly-ohh-zing-boing
哦，夏脉 跑咬一哦一吓一趴
Sca-bee-doo, hoo-bi-dee Zee-boh-doh-zub
叫一哗一嘲，呼一哇一闹 吓一趴一嘟一磁
Diddly-ub-doo-dee-moy
跑咬一么一叶一咬一么
! wanna be a man-man Mon-mon, lorang
妈妈一妈妈
Orangutango-jango
奥雷十唐高一磨高
We got him, King Louie!
我们抓住他了 路易国王 !
Here he is! Man, we got him! We got him!
他在这几! 头儿 我们抓住他了 !
So, you're the man cub.
嘿 你就是那个人孩儿
Crazy!
疯子 !
I'm not as crazy as you are. Put me down!
我没疯 是你疯了 把我放下来 !
You cut that out!
你不要再这样了 !
Cool it, boy. Unwind yourself.
冷静点儿 孩子 放松
Now, come on. Let's shake... cousin.
来吧 我们握握手…表弟
What do you want me for?
你想干什么 ?
Word has grabbed my royal ear...
高贵的我听说…
Have a banana.
先吃个香共
..that you wanna stay in the jungle.
…你想呆在从林里
"Stay in the jungle"? I sure do.
「 有在从林里1 ?我当然想
Good. And ol' King Louie...
好 我是路易国王
That's me.
那是我
..can fix it for you.
…可以帮你实现你的梦想
Have two bananas.
再吃两个
Have we got a deal?
我们就这么定了 ?
Yes, sir, I'll do... I'll do anything to stay in the jungle.
只要采在从林里我什么都愿意
Well, then,
那么好
I'll lay it on the line for you.
为了你我要冒这次险
Now, I'm the king of the swingers, whoa
现在 我是时尚者的国王
The jungle V.LP.
从林里的重要人物
I've reached the top and had to stop
我到达了顶峰不得不停下
And that's what's been botherin' me
这就是让我感到头疫的事情
} wanna be a man, Man Cub and stroll right into town
我想成为人 人和孩儿 大援大摆去进城
And be just like the other men
就像其他的人一样
I'm tired of monkeyin' around
我不愿意在这里当猴子
- Ooh-be-doo - Oop-dee-wee
噢一哗一嘟 噢一哗一咯
- l wanna be like you - Hop-dee-doo-bee-do-bow
我想象你一样…
! wanna walk like you Talk like you
我想像你一样走路 像你一样说话
- Too - Wee-bee-dee-bee-dee-boo
突 哼一哗一吐一哗一跑一中
- You see it's true - Shoo-be-dee-doo
你看这是真的…
- An ape like me - Scooby-doo-bee-doo-bee
像我这样的攻猴…
Can learn to be
也能学得像
Human too
人一样
Wha...?
什么 ?
Gee, Cousin Louie, you're doin’ real good.
嘿 路易表兄 你跳得真好
Now here's your part of the deal, cuz.
现在该轮到你了 表弟
Lay the secret on me of man's red fire.
告诉我 人是怎么生火的
But I don't know how to make fire.
可我不知道怎么生火呀
Now, don't try to kid me, Man Cub
你不要炊骗我 人孩儿
1 made a deal with you
我和你不是说好了
What I desire is man's red fire
我想要的是人类的火种
To make my dream come true
让我的梦想成真
Now give me the secret, Man Cub
现在把秘密告诉我 人孩儿
Come on Clue me what to do
说呀 告诉我该怎么做
Give me the power of man's red flower
给予我人类火焰之花的力量
So can be like you
这样我就能和你一样
Fire? So that's what that scoundrel's after.
火?原来这群无赖 想得到的就是这东西
I'll tear ‘im limb from limb.
我要把他括碎
I'll beat ‘im. I'll... I'll...
我要把他摘扁 我要…
Yeah!
是的!
Well, man, what a beat.
哦 伙计 这节奏冲采了
Will you stop that silly beat business and listen?
你能不能停下那愚夸的节奏 听我说?
This will take brains, not brawn.
我们只能智取 不能训干
You better believe it, and I'm loaded with both.
你别不相信 两者我兼而有之
- Will you listen? - Oh! Yeah, yeah.
你能不能听我说? 哦 !是的 是的
Now, while you create a disturbance,
这样 你去制造混乱
I'll rescue Mowgli.
我去救毛克力
- Got that? - I'm gone, man.
明白了? 我去了 伙计
- Solid gone! - Not yet, Baloo!
真的去了 ! 还没到时候 巴曾 !
Hey, de-zop-ba-nonie
嘿 咬一毗一吧一鹃
Hap-de-dee-ba-lat Da-dat-dat-non
哈一咬一咬一吧一啦 党一哎一莺一鹃
Hey, a-baby-dot-doo Zaba-doo-doo-day-doo-bop
嘿 啊一贝比一哆一叫 咋吧一嘟一叶一得一响一趴
Doo-boo-doo-day, ze-bonz Za-bop-bop-bobby
嘟一踊一嘲一得 咋一踊斯 咋一踊一踊一波比
- Za-bah-doo-dee - Well, a-ree-bah-naza
啼一比一叶一比一叶 鸣，啊一啦一吧一哪
- He-beh-do-beh-doy - Well, a-lah-bah-zini
鸣，啊一啦一吧一毗呢
- Wadahlabat-boodalabat - Seebahlialat-dodie
吗哎啦吧一中营啦吧 晰吧啦啦一叶闹
- Oooh-ooh-ooh - Well, a-ha ha ha
噢噢一噢一嗅 鸣，啊一哈 哈 哈 …
Gettin' mad, baby
发疯吧 伙计
- You-hoo-hoo - Boop-dee-dweet
你一呼一呼 中一跑一喀
- l wanna be like you - Bop-dee-ocobee-doobee
我想和你一样 中一咬一噢比一响比
Talk like you do-ooh-ooh
和你一样说话 嘟一噢一响
- You see it's true-ue-ue - Shoo-be-dee-doo
你看这是真的 竖一比一跑一嘟
- Someone like me - Scooby-dooby-dooby
像我这样的人 中一咯比一咯比
Can learn to be like someone like me
可以学着成为别人 像我这样
Take me home, daddy
带我回家 和区和区
Can learn to be like someone like you
可以学着成为别人 像你一样
- One more time - Yeah!
再唱一遍 是的!
Can learn to be like someone like me
可以学着成为别人 像我一样
- It's Baloo, the bear! - Yeah, that's him!
是巴鲁 是狗熊 ! 对 是他!
How'd that square get in there?
这家伙是怎么进来的?
Baloo! It's you!
巴鲁!是你!
Man, that's what I call a swingin’ party!
伙计 这就是我所说的 摇滚派对
And furthermore, Baloo,
还有 巴鲁
Mowgli seems to have man's ability to get into trouble,
看来毛克力有人类 应付麻烦的能力
and your influence hasn't been exactly...
你的影响还不足以…
Keep it down. You're gonna wake up little buddy.
小声 点儿 你会把那个小家伙吵醒的
Well, he's had a big day.
他今天累坏了
You know, it ain't easy learnin' to be like me.
你知道跟我学东西不容易
A disgraceful performance.
丢人的表演
Associating with those undesirable, scatterbrained apes?
和那些不受欢迎的 毛躁的猿猴打交道 ?
l hope Mowgli learned something from that experience.
我希望毛克力能从这次 经历中学到点儿什么
Scooby-dooby-dooby Dooby-doo
号比一叶比一咯比 嘻比一叶
That's my boy.
真是个好孩子
Oh, nonsense.
哦 一派胡言
Baloo.
巴重
Over here. I'd like to have a word with you.
过来 我要跟你说白话
"A word"? You gonna talk some more?
「说名话」 ?你还没说完?
All right, what's up, Bagheera?
好了 说吧 巴赫拉?
Baloo,
巴重
the man cub must go back to the man-village.
人和孩儿必须回到 人类尾住的村庄
The jungle is not the place for him.
从林不是他呆的地方
I grew up in the jungle. Take a look at me.
我就是在丛林中长大的 你看我
Yes, just look at yourself.
是的 看看你自己吧
Look at that eye.
看看那只眼睛
Yeah.
是的
It's beautiful, ain't it?
真漂亮 不是吗?
Frankly, you're a disreputable sight.
坦率地讲 你的形象狼狐不堪
Well, you don't look exactly like a basket of fruit yourself.
不过 你也好不到哪儿去
Baloo,
巴重
you can't adopt Mowgli as your son.
你不能收养毛克力作儿子
Why not?
为什么 ?
How can I put it?
怎么跟你说呢 ?
Baloo,
巴重
birds of a feather should flock together.
物以类票
You wouldn't marry a panther, would you?
你不打算和黑豹结婚吧 ?
I don't know.
我不知道
Come to think of it, no panther ever asked me.
有意思 还没有一只黑鹏这样问过我
Oh, Baloo, you've got to be serious about this.
哦 巴鲁 这事儿 你必须严肃对等
Oh, stop worryin', Baggy. Stop worryin’.
哦 不用担心 巴赫拉 不用担心
I'll take care of him.
我会照顾他的
Yes, like you did when the monkeys kidnapped him, huh?
是的 就像猴子绑架他时 你的所作所为 ?
- Can't a guy make one mistake? - Not in the jungle.
难道人就不能犯错误吗 ? 在丛林中就不能
And another thing,
还有
sooner or later Mowgli will meet Shere Khan.
迟早 毛克力会遇到施亚汗
The tiger? What's he got against the kid?
那只老虎?为什么 他非要和这孩子过不去
He hates man with a vengeance. You know that.
他想复做 他痛恨人类 这你知道
Because he fears man's gun and man's fire.
因为他害怕人类的枪和火
But little Mowgli don't have those things.
可是小毛克力 并没有这些东西
Shere Khan won't wait until he does.
施亚汗不会等到那一天的
He'll get Mowgli while he's young and helpless.
他会趁毛克力年轻 无助的时候抢先下手
Just one swipe and...
只需一巴掌打下去…
Well, what are we gonna do?
那我们该怎么办?
We'll do what's best for the boy.
怎么对孩子有好处 我们就怎么做
You better believe it. You name it, and I'll do it.
相信我 你说怎么做 我就怎么做
Good. Then make Mowgli go to the man-village.
好 证毛克力回到 人类尾住的村庄
Are you out of your mind?
你鸳了吗 ?
I promised him he could stay here in the jungle with me.
我向他保证过 他可以 在丛林中和我一起生活
That's just the point.
问题就在这几
As long as he remains with you, he's in danger.
只要他和你采在这几 他就处在危险之中
- So it's up to you. - Why me?
现在就看你了 为什么是我 ?
Because he won't listen to me.
因为他不青听我的
I love that kid.
我喜欢这孩子
I love him like he was my own cub.
我爱他就像爱自己的孩子一样
Then think of what's best for Mowgli and not yourself.
不要为自己着想 要多为毛克力想想
Well, can't...
不过…-
Can't I wait until morning?
能不能等到明天早上?
It's morning now.
现在就是早上了
Go on, Baloo.
去吧 巴曾
Oh, boy.
莪 孩子
Mowgli. Mowgli.
毛克力 毛克力
It's time to get up.
该起床了
Oh. Hi, Baloo.
哦 你好 巴恒
Hi.
你好
Hey, rub that ol’ sleep outta your eyes.
嘿 该醒醒了
You and me, we got a long walk ahead of us.
你和我 今天还要走 很长一段路
Swell. We'll have lots of fun together.
太好了 我们可以 一起好好玩儿了
Sure. Yeah. Yeah.
当然 是的 是的
All right, let's hit the trail, kid.
好了 我们赶路吧 孩子
See ya around, uh, Bagheera.
再见了 巴赫拉
Me and Baloo, we've got things to do.
我和巴鲁 我们有事情要做
Goodbye, Man Cub...
再见 人孩儿…
..and good luck.
…祝你好运
Come on, Baloo.
快来 巴鲁
All we gotta do is...
我们要做的是…
Look for the bare necessities
寻找必需品
Some good ol' bare necessities
一些好的必需品
Forget about your worries and your strife
忘掉你的烦恼和争吵
1 mean, the bare necessities
我是说 必须品
That's why a bear can rest at ease
这就是为什么 狗熊可以遂东自在
With just the bare necessities of life
只索取生活必需品
Yeah!
是的!
I'll live here in the jungle all my life
我要一辈子在这里 在丛林中生活
Yeah, man! I like being a bear.
是的 伙计 ! 像一头真正的焦
Where we goin’, Baloo?
我们去哪儿 巴鲁?
Well, it's...
我们去…
Well, it's sorta new and...
是一个新的什么…
Oh, I don't care, as long as I'm with you.
哦 不管到哪儿 只要和你在一起
Mowgli... look, buddy, there's somethin’ I gotta tell ya.
毛克力…听着 伙计 有些事情我得告诉你
Tell me what, Baloo?
告诉我什么 巴鲁?
Oh, gee whiz.
哦…天啊
Now, how did ol’ Baggy put it? It's...
巴赫拉是怎么说的来着 ? 它…-
Mowgli...
毛克力…
You wouldn't marry a panther, would ya?
你不会和一只黑豹结婚 对吧?
Gee, I don't even know what you're talking about.
嗨 我不知道你在说什么
Mowgli, don't you realize that you're a human?
毛克力 你难道不明白 你是个人类吗?
I'm not anymore, Baloo. I'm a bear like you.
我已经不再是了 巴重 我是狗熊 和你一样
- Little buddy, look, listen to me. - Come on, Baloo!
小饮伴 听我说 快来 巴鲁!
Mowgli, stop it now. Hold still.
毛克力 别并了 不要动
l wanna tell you something. Now listen to me.
我想和你说句话 现在听我说
What's the matter, ol' Papa Bear?
怎么啦 老熊区葡 ?
Look, Mowgli, I've been tryin’ all morning to tell ya,
听着 毛克力 整个早晨 我一直不知道该怎么对你说
I've got to take you back to the man-village.
我要把你送到 人类属住的村庄去
- The man-village? - Now, look, kid, I can explain.
人类履住的村庄 ? 听着 孩子 我可以解释
- But you said we were partners. - Now, believe me, kid, I...
可你说过不分开的 相信我 孩子 我…
- You're just like old Bagheera. - Now just a minute!
你和老巴赫拉一样 等一下 !
That's goin’ too far!
这太过分了 !
Hey, Mowgli! Where you goin'?
嘿 毛克力 1你要去哪儿 ?
Wait a minute! Stop!
等一下1站住!
Wait!
等一下 !
Wait! Listen to ol’ Baloo!
等等 ! 听我说 !
Mowgli!
毛克力!
Mowgli. Mowgli!
毛克力 1 毛克力!
Now what's happened?
怎么回事儿 ?
Well, you're not gonna believe me, Bagheera,
你不会相信的 巴赫拉
but look, now, I used the same words you did, and he ran out on me!
我用你曾经说过的那些话 对他说 可他却跑了 !
Well, don't just stand there.
别傻站在那儿了
Let's separate. We've got to find him!
我们分头去找 得找到他 !
Oh, if anything happens to that little guy, I'll never forgive myself.
哦 如果发生什么意外 我不会原谅自己的
I gotta find him.
我得找到他
Mowgli!
毛克力!
Hup, two, three, four
二三四
Keep it up, two, three, four
跟上队伍 二 三 四
What beastly luck.
真倒霉
Confound that ridiculous Colonel Hathi.
让那个可笑的哈蒂上校给搅了
Company... sound off!
全体都有…唱!
Oh, we march from here to there
哦 我们从这里走到那里
And it doesn't matter where
不管在什么地方
You can hear us push through the deepest bush
你都能听到我们 穿越从林的步伐
Hup, two, three, four
二三四
With a military air
以严整的军容
The jungle patrol!
从林巡逮队 !
We're a crackerjack brigade
我们是强人之旅
On a pachyderm parade
在进行厚皮类动物的队列行进
But we'd rather strolf to a water hole
可我们更愿意迈步走向水闹
Hup, two, three, four
二三四
For a furlough in the shade
在凉硼中休整
Stop!
站住!
Wait a minute. Halt!
怎么说来着 ? 立定 !
Who said "halt"? I give the commands around here.
谁喊的「立定」 ? 这里只有我才能喊口令
Well, speak up. Who was it?
说吧 是谁喊的?
Oh, it was me, Colonel.
哦 是我 上校
What do you mean, sir, taking over my command? Highly irregular, you know.
你想干什么 先生 想夺权? 这太无法无天了 知道吗
Oh, Colonel, I'm sorry, but I need your help.
哦 上校 抱娄 不过我需要你的帮助
Oh, absolutely impossible.
哦 不可能
We're on a cross-country march.
我们在进行越野行军
But it's an emergency, Colonel.
可这件事很紧急 上校
- The man cub must be found. - Man cub? What man cub?
必须要找到人孩儿 人孩儿?什么人孩儿 ?
How interesting.
太有意思了
The one I was taking to the man-village.
我要送到人类村庄去的那个
Good. That's where he belongs.
很好 那是他该呆的地方
Now, sir, if you don't mind, we'd like to get on with the march.
现在 先生 如果不介意的话 我们还要继续行军
No, no, you don't understand, Hathi.
不 不 你不明白 哈切
He is lost. He ran away.
他和雪了 跑掉了
How delightful.
太好了
Well, it serves the young whippersnapper right.
那个自以为了不起的年轻人 罪有应得
But Shere Khan, the tiger,
可是施亚汗 那只老虎
is sure to pick up the man cub's trail.
背定会尾随人孩儿
Shere Khan. Nonsense, old boy.
施亚汗 一派胡言 老弟
Shere Khan isn't within miles of here.
方圆几英里哪有施亚汗的踪影
Oh, sorry, Bagheera. Fortunes of war and all that sort of thing, you know.
哦 抱火 巴赫拉 你知道 战争之类的东西
This has gone far enough.
已经离我们远去了
Far enough!
不会再有了 !
Now, just a minute, you pompous old windbag!
等一下 你这个华而不实的老东西 !
Winifred! What are you doing out of ranks?
威妮弗蔓德 ! 你到队列 外面做什么 ?
Never mind.
你别管
How would you like to have our boy lost and alone in the jungle?
我们的孩子在从林中迷路 你会怎么样 ?
Our son... alone?
我们的儿子…一个人 ?
But, Winifred, old girl, that's an entirely different matter.
可是 威妮悦蔓德 这完全是两码事儿
Different, entirely.
不同 完全不同
That little boy is no different than our own son.
那个孩子和我们的儿子 没什么不同
Now you help find him or I'm taking over command.
要么你帮忙去找他 要么我就接管你的指挥权
What? A female leading my herd?
什么?女人来指挥我的象群 ?
Utterly preposterous.
这太荒廖了
Pop, the man cub and I are friends.
和爸爸 那个人孩儿是我的朋友
He'll get hurt if we don't find him.
如果不找到他 他会受伤的
Please, Pop, sir? Please?
求你了 各和钨 长官? 拜托了?
Now, don't you worry, son.
好了 别担心 儿子
Your father had a plan in mind all the time.
你父亲什么时候都运筹肉慢
Sure you did.
你当然是的
Troopers!
战士们 !
Company... left face!
全体都有…向左转 !
Volunteers for a special mission
愿意执行特殊任务的志愿者
will step one pace forward.
向前一步走
That's what I like to see.
这是我所愿意看到的
Devotion to duty.
患于职守
Now, you volunteers will find the lost man cub.
现在你们这些志愿者 出发寻找那名失踪的人孩儿
Oh, thank you, Colonel. There's no time to lose.
哦 谢谢你 上校! 可得抓紧呀
Yes. Yes.
是的 是的
Bugler, when the man cub is sighted,
号手 发现人孩儿之后
you will sound your trumpet three times.
吹三声喇叭
Yes, sir.
是的 长官
Not now, soldier.
别现在吹 士兵
Sorry, sir.
抱散 长官
Lieutenant, our strategy shall be the element of surprise.
中尉 我们的战略是 突然克击
You will take one squad and cover the right flank.
你率领一个小组 负责帮权掩扩
Yes, sir.
是 长官
And I shall meet the other squad on the left flank.
我将和另一个小组 在左权会合
Very well.
很好
Compary...
全体都有….
.. forward... march!
…正前方…章步走 !
Element of surprise?
突然克击?
Oh, I say.
哦 我说
And now for my rendezvous
我现在要去和
with the little lost man cub.
那个失踪的人孩儿会合
Kaa! It's you!
卡奥 是你!
Yes-s-s, Man Cub.
是的 人孩儿
So nice to see you again.
又一赤见到你真是太好了
Oh, go away. Leave me alone.
走开 别烦我
Let me look at you.
让我看看你
You don't want me to look at you?
你不想让我看你吗 ?
Then you look at me.
那你看我好了
No, sir. l know what you're trying to do, Kaa.
不 先生 我知道 你想干什么 卡奥
You do?
是吗?
I mean, you don't trust me.
我是说 你不相信我
- No. - Then there's nothing I can do to help.
不 那我就无能为力了
You want to help me?
你想帮助我?
Certainly.
当然
I can see to it...
我可以保证…
. that you never have to leave this jungle.
…你永远不离开这片从林
How could you do that?
你有什么办法?
Hmm?
另?
Oh, I have my own...
哦 我有我自己的…
But first, you must trust me.
但是 你首先得信任我
I don't trust anyone anymore.
我谁也不信了
I don't blame you.
我不会责备你
I'm not like those so-called
我不像你的那些所谓
fair-weather friends of yours.
不能共惠难的朋友
You can believe in me.
你可以相信我
Trust in me
相信我
Just in me
只相信我
Shut your eyes
闭上你的眼睛
And trust in me
相信我
Hold still, please.
请等一下
You can sleep
你可以睡觉
Safe and sound
美美地隆上一觉
Knowing!
知道我就
Am around
在你的周转
Slip into silent slumber
滑进了宁静的梦香中
Sail on a silver mist
在银色的薄雾中起航
Slowly and surely
慢慢地 坚定地
Your senses will cease to resist
你的知觉将停止抵抗
You're snoring.
你在打身
Sorry.
抱攻
Trust in me
相信我
Shut your eyes
闭上你的眼睛
Huh?
哦 ?
Oh, now what?
哦 怎么了?
I'll be right down.
我马上下来
Yes? Yes? Who is it?
是的?是的?是谁呀?
It's me, Shere Khan.
是我 施亚汗
I'd like a word with you, if you don't mind.
如果不介意的话 我想和你说句话
Shere Khan. What a s-s-surprise.
施亚汗 真没想到
Yes, isn't it? I just dropped by.
是吗?我只是路过这里
Forgive me if I've interrupted anything.
如果说打扰了 请你原谅
Oh, no, no. Nothing at all.
哦 不不没人关系
I thought perhaps you were entertaining someone up there in your coils.
我想你在上面 正盘着一个人玩要
Coils? Someone? Oh, no.
盘着?一个人?哦 不
l was just curling up for my siesta.
我正盘着身子睡午觉
But you were singing to someone.
可你正在给一个人唱歌
- Who is it, Kaa? - Who?
那是谁 卡奥? 谁?
Oh, no.
哦 不
- was just singing to myself. - Indeed.
我在和我自己说话
Yes. Yes, you see, l have trouble with my s-s-sinuses.
是的 是的 你看 我的身体不舒服
- What a pity. - Oh, you have no idea.
哦 你不知道
It's simply terrible. I can't eat.
太可怕了 我无法吃东西
I can't s-s-sleep, sol sing myself to sleep.
无法睡觉 所以我自己唱歌想办法睡觉
You know, self-hypnosis?
你知道 自我催耻术吗?
Let me show you how it works.
我做一下让你看看
Trust in me
相信我
I can't be bothered with that.
你这套玩意儿对我没用
l have no time for that sort of nonsense.
我没时间看你这套鬼把戏
- Some other time, perhaps? - Perhaps.
以后再说吧 或许? 或许
But at the moment lam searching for a man cub.
不过现在 我在寻找一个人孩儿
"Man cub"? What man cub?
[人和孩儿」 ? 什么人孩儿 ?
The one who's lost.
一个迷路的人孩儿
Now, where do you suppose he could be?
你觉得他现在应该在哪儿 ?
Search me.
搜一搜
That's an excellent idea.
这主意真不错
I'm sure you wouldn't mind showing me your coils, would you, Kaa?
我想你不会介意让我 检查一下你吧 卡奥?
Certainly not.
当然不
Nothing here,
这几没有什么
and nothing in here.
这儿也没有什么
My sinuses.
是我的胃
Indeed.
的确
And now, how about the middle?
你身体的中间一段呢?
The middle?
中间一般?
Oh, the middle.
哦 中间一段
Absolutely nothing in the middle.
中间一段也没什么
Really?
真的?
Well, if you do just happen to see the man cub,
好吧 如果你碰巧看到 那个人孩儿
you will inform me first.
一定要先通知我
- Understand? - [get the point.
明白了吗? 我明白了
- Cross my heart, hope to die. - Good show.
我在胸口划十字 对天发拆 表现不错
And I must continue my search for the helpless little lad.
我必须继续寻找 那个无动的孩子
Who does he think he's fooling?
他以为他骗得了谁?
"Helpless little lad."
「 无动的孩子1
Ooh, he gives me the s-s-shivers.
哦 他吓得我浑身直哆唆
Picking on that poor little helpless boy.
选中那个可怜 无了助的孩子
Oh, yes.
哦 是的
The poor little helpless boy.
可怜无助的孩子
You told me a lie, Kaa. You said I could trust you.
你对我撒谎了 卡奥 你说过我可以相信你
It's like you said.
你不是说过吗
You can't trust anyone.
不能相信任何人
If l never see that skinny little shrimp again,
如果我再也看不到那个 小瘦是米了
it will be too soon.
这可就太快了
Ooh, my s-s-sacroiliac.
哦 我的跑骨
Hey, Flaps. What we gonna do?
嘿 弗菜小斯 我们干什么 ?
I don't know. What do you wanna do?
我不知道 你想和干什么 ?
I've got it! Let's flap over to the east side of the jungle.
我有了 到从林东边儿去转转
They've always got a bit of action, a bit of a swingin’ scene.
那边总会发生什么事几 总会有些扬滚的场景
Aw, come off it! Things are right dead all over.
哦 别连说了 ! 那边儿的东西都死光了
You mean you wish they were.
你是说你希望他们死掉
Very funny.
有意思
OK, so what we gonna do?
好吧 那我们干什么 ?
I don't know. What do you wanna do?
我不知道 你想和干什么 ?
Look, Flaps, first l say, "What we gonna do?"
看 悦莱波斯 我先说 「 我们干什么? 1
Then you say, "I don't know. What do you wanna do?"
然后你说【我不知道 你想干什么? 1
"What we gonna do?" "What you wanna do?"
「 我们干什么? 1 「 你想干什么?1
What we gonna do, what you want... Let's do something!
我们干什么 你想干… 我们总该干点儿什么吧 !
OK. What do you want to do?
好吧 你想千什么 ?
Oh, blimey. There you go again.
啊呀 你怎么又来了
The same notes again.
总是同样的话
I've got it! This time, I've really got it.
我有了!这炊 我真的有了
So you've got it. So what we gonna do?
这么说你有主意了 那么我们干什么 ?
Hold it, lads. Look. Look what's coming our way.
等等 伙计们 你们看 有个东西在朝这边儿过来了
Hey, what in the world is that?
嘿 那究竟是什么东西 ?
What a crazy looking bunch of bones.
是什么东西这么叶瘦如此
Yeah, and they're all walking about by themselves.
是的 好像是骨头自己在走路
- So what we gonna do? - [don't know.
那我们做什么呢? 我不知道
Hey, now, don't start that again.
嘿 别再重复了
Come on, lads. Come on.
来吧 伙计们 来
Let's have some fun with this little fella, this little bloke, eh?
我们去和这个小家伙开个玩笑 怎么样 ?
Blimey! He's got legs like a stork, he has.
啊呀 ! 他长着腿 像鸥一样
Like a stork. Ha ha! But he ain't got no feathers, he ain't.
像是一只鸥 哈哈 ! 可他没有羽毛 他不是
Go ahead. Laugh. I don't care.
说吧 笑吧 我不在卑
What's wrong with him?
他怎么了?
I think we overdid it.
我想我们做得过火了
We were just having a bit of fun, that's all.
我们只是开了个小小的玩笑 仅此而已
Oh, just look at him. Why, the poor little fella.
哦 你们看他那样几 可怜的小家伙
You know, he must be down on his luck.
他篆定遇到什么不幸了
Yeah, or he wouldn't be in our neighborhood.
是的 要不然 他不会到我们这儿来
Hey, new kid! Wait a minute! Hey!
嘿 新来的小孩儿 等一下工嘿!
Just leave me alone.
别烦我
Oh, come on. What's wrong?
哦 说出来 怎么啦 ?
You look like you haven't got a friend in the world.
在这个世界上 你看来没有一个朋友
- [haven't. - Haven't you got a mother or a father?
我没有 那你总得有和多答和妈妈吧 ?
No. Nobody wants me around.
没有 没有人喜欢我
Yeah. We know how you feel.
是的 我们能体会你的感受
Nobody wants us around either.
也没有人喜欢我们
Oh, we may look a bit shabby, but we've got hearts.
哦 我们看起来衣冠不整 但我们的心肠不错
And feelings too.
富有同情心
And just to prove it to you,
为了向你证明这一点
we're going to let you join our little group.
我们准备邀请你 成为我们的一员
Kid, we'd like to make you an honorary vulture.
孩子 我们想把你塑造成 一只荣誉秃认
Thanks, but I... I'd rather be on my own alone.
谢谢 可我… 我宁可自己一个人时着
Oh, now, look, kid.
哦 你看 孩子
Everybody's got to have friends.
每个人都得有朋友
Hey, fellas, are we his friends?
嘿 伙伴们 我们是不是他的朋友 ?
We're your friends
我们是你的朋友
We're your friends to the bitter end
直到那痛苦的终点
The bitter end
冯苦的终点
When you're alone
当你孤独的时候
Who comes around
谁来到身边
To pluck you up
让你打起精神
- Give us a smile. - To pluck you up
冲我们笑一笑 打起业神
When you are down
当你肖责的时候
And when you're outside looking in
当你在外面往里看
Who's there to open the door?
谁来给你把门开?
- Come on, kid. We need a tenor. - That's
来 孩子 我们需要个男高音 对
What
什么
Friends are for
朋友是那些
Who's always eager to extend
始终渴望帮助别人的人
A friendly claw
友谊的直子
That's what friends are for
这就是为什么我们需要朋友
And when you're lost
当你迷路的时候
In dire need
需要帮忙的时候
Who's at your side
谁在你的身边
At lightning speed
以闪电般的速度
We're friends with every creature comin' down the pike
我们和所有的人都是朋友
In fact, we've never met an animal we didn't like
其实我们从未遇到过 任何我们不喜欢的动物
You take it, kid.
请你相信 孩子
Didn't like
不喜欢的
- So, you can see we're friends - Friends in need
所以你可以明白我们是朋友 囊难之交
We're friends in need and friends indeed
我们是患难之交 是真正的朋友
Friends indeed
真正的朋友
Oh, friends indeed
哦 真正的朋友
- Easy, lads. Steady. Watch it! - We'll keep you safe in the jungle
放松 伙计们 站稳 小心! 我们会保证你在从林中的安全
Forevermore
永远
That's what friends
这是为什么我们
Are for
需要朋友
Bravo. Bravo.
很好 很好
An extraordinary performance.
非常精彩的表演
And thank you for detaining my victim.
谢谢你们留住了我的受害人
Uh, don't mention it, Your Highness.
哦 别客气 殿下
Boo!
中1!
- Let's get out of here. - Gimme room! Gangway!
快离开这几 别挡着我的路 !
Run, friend! Run!
快跑 朋友 !快跑!
"Run"? Why should I run?
[跑」 ?我为什么要跑?
Why should you run?
你为什么要跑 ?
Could it be possible that you don't know who I am?
可能你还不知道我是谁吧 ?
I know you, all right.
我知道你是谁 明白吗
- You're Shere Khan. - Precisely.
你是施亚汗 非常正确
Then you should also know that everyone runs from Shere Khan.
那么你也应该知道 所有人见了施亚汗都要跑的
You don't scare me. I won't run from anyone.
你吓距不了我 无论见到谁我都不会跑
Ah! You have spirit for one so small,
啊 ! 你人不大却很勇敢
and such spirit is deserving of a sporting chance.
这样勇敢的人应该 给他一灾逃命的机会
Now, I'm going to close my eyes and count to ten.
现在我闭上了眼睛数10下
It makes the chase more interesting... for me.
这样追起来更有意思… 对我来说
One...
-一
... two, three...
=     一
. four...
四.…-
You're trying my patience.
你在挑战我的耐心
. five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten.
…和五六七入九王
Run, Mowgli, run!
快跑 毛克力 快跑!
Let go, you big oaf!
松手 你个果子 !
Take it easy. Take it easy.
别激动 别激动
Hold it. Hold it. Hold it. Whoa!
抓住 抓住 抓住 哇!
Whoa, slow! Easy, now!
哇 慢点儿 ! 别激动 !
Whoa! Easy!
哇 !别激动 !
He's got a tiger by the tail, he has.
他抓住了老虎的尾巴
And he better hang on too.
他最好能坚持住
Take that, you big bully.
让你尝尝这个 你这个竺强凌弱的家伙
Let him have it again, kid! Hit him again, kid! Go on!
再给他一下 孩子 狠狠地打 孩子 继续打 !
Baloo! Help me!
巴鲁 !救救我 !
Somebody do something with that kid!
谁来帮一下那个孩子 !
Come on, lads!
来吧 伙计们1!
He's safe now! Ha ha ha! You can let go, Baloo.
他现在安全了 ! 哈哈哈 ! 你可以放手了 巴重
Are you kiddin’? There's teeth in the other end.
你不是在开玩笑吧? 那边儿可是有牙的
I'll kill you for this.
看来我非杀了你不可
Let go! Baloo needs help!
放开 ! 巴鲁需要帮手 !
Fire! That's the only thing Old Stripes is afraid of.
火!这是那个老斑纹 唯一害怕的东西
You get the fire. We'll do the rest.
你去拿火 我们负责其他的
Charge!
冲啊!
- Punch and blow! - Stay out of this, you mangy fools!
狠狠地打 ! 躲开 你们这些卑部的白疯 !
Yeah, yeah. Missed me a mile, he did!
是的 是的 他没打着我 !
Yeah, pull his blinkin' whiskers!
是的 拔了他的胡子 !
He's a bloomin' pussycat, he is!
他可真是个讨人喜欢的家伙 !
Look behind you, chum.
看看你身后 亲爱的
Well, that's the last of him.
好了 他终于跑了
Old Stripes took off like a flaming comet, he did.
老斑纹跑了 就像是冒着火的丰星
Well, come on. Let's go congratulate our friend.
走 去向我们的朋友祝贺去
Hold it, fellas.
慢着 伙计们
Now is not the time for it. Look.
现在还不是时候 看
Baloo?
巴鲁?
Baloo, get up.
巴鲁 起来
Oh, please, get up.
哦 拜托你了 起来呀
Mowgli, try to understand.
毛克力 好好想想
Bagheera, what's the matter with him?
巴赫拉 他怎么啦?
You've got to be brave, like Baloo was.
你要勇至些 像巴恒那样
You... You don't mean...
你…你是说…
Oh, no. Baloo.
哦 不 巴鲁
Now, now. I know how you feel.
好了 好了 我知道你难受
But you must remember, Mowgli,
但是你必须记住 毛克力
"Greater love hath no one
「人的爱心没有比
than he who lays down his life for his friend."
为朋友献出生命更伟大的了1
When great deeds
当从林里传令着
are remembered in this jungle,
伟大的功绩时
one name will stand above all others:
一个名字会赫然屹立
Our friend, Baloo the bear.
我们的朋友 狗熊巴重
He's crackin’ me up.
他都把我说器了
The memory of Baloo's sacrifice and bravery
对巴章牺牲和对他勇敢行为 的回忆
will forever be engraved on our saddened hearts.
将永远地镜刻在 我们沉痛的心中
Beautiful.
太美了
This spot where Baloo fell will always be
巴鲁倒下去的这片土地 将永远地成为
a hallowed place in the jungle,
从林中最神圣的地方
for there lies one of nature's noblest creatures.
因为这里躺着一位 自然界中最高尚的生命
I wish my mother could have heard this.
能够听到这些话
It's best we leave now.
我们最好还是离开吧
Come along, Man Cub.
走吧 人孩儿
Hey, don't stop now, Baggy. You're doin’ great!
嘿 继续说呀 巴赫拉 你说得太好了 !
There's more. Lots more!
还有呢 还有好多好多 !
Why, you big fraud!
怎么 你个大骗子 !
You four-flusher!
你个骗人的家伙 !
I'm fed up!
我厌倦了 !
Baloo, you're all right!
巴鲁 你没事儿吧 !
Who, me? Sure lam.
谁 我?当然没事几
Never felt... better.
从来没感觉过这么好
- You sure had us worried. - l was just takin' five.
你可把我们吓坏了 我刚刚是在休息
You know, playin’ it cool.
你知道 假装冷静
- But he was too easy. - Good old Papa Bear.
可他大容易被骗了 我的好狗熊和区和区
It's going to be a bit dull without the little bloke, isn't it?
没有了那小子就有些无聊了 对吧?
Yeah. So what we gonna do?
是的 那我们干什么 ?
I don't know... Now, don't start that again!
我不知道… 哦 别再这么说了行不行 !
Hey, Baggy. Too bad you missed the action.
嘿 巴赫拉 你没参加战斗真太遗憾了
You should have seen how I made a sucker
你真该看看 我是怎么收失
out of Old Stripes with that left up in his face.
那只老斑纹的 在他的脸上留下了印记
"Boom, boom," I was givin’ him. "Wham!"
「呼上 我给了他一记「重拳]
Wanna know somethin'? We're good sparring partners.
知道吗? 我们是 最好的拳击搭档
- You'd better believe it. - Yes, sir.
那当然了 是的 先生
Nothing or nobody is ever gonna come between us again.
没有任何东西 任何人 可以把我们再一灵分开了
My own home
我自己的家园
Look! What's that?
看1!那是什么?
- Oh, it's the man-village. - No, no. l mean that.
哦 那是人类居住的村庄 不 不 我是说那个
Forget about those. They ain't nothing but trouble.
别理会那些东西 他们只会带来麻烦
Just a minute. I've never seen one before.
稍微等一下 我以前还没有见过
So you've seen one. So let's go.
你这不是见到了吗 走吧
I'll be right back. l want a better look.
我马上就回来 我想好好看看
- Mowgli, wait a minute! - Oh, Baloo.
毛克力 等一下 哦 巴章
Let him have a better look.
让他好好看看吧
Father's hunting in the forest
父亲打猎在从林
Mother's cooking in the home
母亲做饭在家中
! must go to fetch the water
我必须前来把水取
Till the day that l am grown
直到我长大的那一天
Till 'm grown
直到我长大
! must go to fetch the water
我必须前来把水取
Till the day that l am grown
直到我长大的那一天
Then I will have a handsome husband
我会嫁一个漂亮的支夫
And a daughter of my own
生一个我自己的女儿
And I'll send her to fetch the water
我会让她来取水
I'l be cooking in the home
我将做饭在家中
- She did that on purpose! - Obviously.
她这样做是故意的! 很明显
Mowgli, come back. Come back.
毛克力 回来 回来
Go on. Go on.
去吧 去吧
He's hooked.
他被匀引了
It was inevitable, Baloo.
这是不可避免的 巴重
The boy couldn't help himself.
男孩子情不自森
It was bound to happen.
这种事儿迟早要发生
Mowgli is where he belongs now.
毛克力回到了属于他的地方
Yeah.
是的
I guess you're right.
我想你是对的
But I still think he'd have made one swell bear.
不过我仍然认为 他能成为一只出色的狗熊
Well, come on, Baggy, buddy.
好了 走吧 巴赫拉
Let's get back to where we belong.
让我们打道回府 回属于我们自己的地方
And get with the beat.
跟着节奏
Look for the bare necessities
寻找必需品
The simple bare necessities
简简单单的必需品
Forget about your worries and your strife
忘掉你的烦恼和争吵
1 mean the bare necessities
我是说必需品
Are Mother Nature's recipes
是大地之母的误饪方法
That bring the bare necessities of life
给予了我们生活的必需品